Clara Barton Papers, 1882-1982
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES V. MEMORABILIA AND PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Photographs
    - Cemetery plot where Clara Barton is buried (4 snapshots, 1 postcard), undated (Box 6)
    - Universalist Church, Oxford, MA (postcard), undated (Box 6)
    - Andersonville memorabilia, undated (Box 6)
- SERIES VI. KENSEL-WELLS FAMILY
  - Personal material
    - Correspondence, 1890-1919 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Memorabilia, [see also Oversize materials]
      - Miscellaneous, 1865-1911 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Scrapbook, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Mary Kensel Wells, writing, 1935-60 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - National First Aid Association of America
    - Annual reports (1-4), 1906-09 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Publications, 1906-20 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Certificate, incorporation papers, and letter from Clara Barton, 1905-07 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Memorabilia, [see also Oversize materials] (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Red Cross, 1895-96, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Clara Barton
    - Correspondence, 1906-12 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1879-1929 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, 1917-82 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Memorabilia, 1900-24, undated, [see also Oversize materials] (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Flags
    - Clara Barton Staff colors (Box 9)
    - Clara Barton Ambulance Corps colors (Box 9)
  - Women's Relief Corps medals (Box 10)
  - Civil War relics
    - Sewing kit and miscellaneous fragments from Civil War battlefields (Box 11)
    - Civil War belt buckles (Box 11)
    - Fragment of a Bible, baking pan, and spoon from Andersonville Prison (Box 11)
    - Civil War money (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia
    - Violet from a bonnet worn by Clara Barton (Box 12)
    - National First Aid Association medals and pins (7) (Box 12)
    - Pin of the St. John ambulance Association from it's first meeting, 1906 (Box 12)
    - Assorted buttons, medal, 10 cent piece from canteen at Fort Warren, 2 small gifts presented to several of her friends by Clara Barton (Box 12)
    - Pin: "Recuerdo" (Box 12)
    - Copper plate with image of Clara Barton (Box 12)
  - G.A. Kensel certificate of promotion to Colonel, 1865 (Map-case Flat file)
  - Roscoe Wells' certificate of appointment to Major General in Clara Barton Ambulance Corps (Map-case Flat file)
  - Photo of flags (NFAA?) (Map-case Flat file)
  - Photo of NFAA with Clara Barton and Roscoe Wells (Map-case Flat file)
  - Portrait of Clara Barton (2 copies) (Map-case Flat file)
  - Framed signed portrait of Clara Barton (Map-case Flat file)
- VOLUMES ON SHELF
  - Bound volume of clippings: reviews of William Barton biography
  - Barton, William E., The Life of Clara Barton, Founder of the American Red Cross. (Boston: Houghton Mifflin), 1922 (2 vols.)
  - Epler, Percy H., The Life of Clara Barton (New York: Macmillan Co.), 1915
  - Williams, Blanche Colton, Clara Barton, Daughter of Destiny (New York, Lippincott), 1941
  - Rhode Island. Joint Special Committee on Erections of Monument at Andersonville, Ga. Report. (Providence, E. L. Freeman & Sons, State Printers, 1903 )